DIVINE CHUKWUDIRE

Port Harcourt, Nigeria

Summary

Experienced Software Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the Software industry. Skilled in English, Html, Dart, Css, Wordpress, mySQL, React, Bootstrap, Json, Javascript, Project management, and Python (Programming Language). Strong Information technology professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Information Technology from Salem University Lokoja Kogi state.

Skills

- Javascript (Node.js, Next.js, MongoDB, React.js)
- Python (Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, matplotlib)
- Flutter (Dart)
- Excel (VLOOKUP, Conditional Formatting, Pivot Tables)
- Microsoft Azure (DataBricks, Azure Data Lake, Azure Data Warehouse)
- Html and Css
- React

Work Experience

Software Engineer Turing

March 2023 - Till Date

- Translated basic design plans into full Android app frameworks, delegation project components to appropriate team
- Involved in the entire software development process for the project. Requirement Specification, Design, implementation, and Testing.
- Maintaining existing mobile applications by designing patches to be applied via IOS automatic updates.
- Applied Agile software methodology to elevate final products and streamline development efforts.
- Researched and selected APIs for integration into development projects.
- Designed user experience frameworks applicable to multiple screen sizes, including both IPad and IPhone.

Database Manager Okmas Limited, Port Harcourt Nigeria March 2022 – Februrary 2023

- Identified, analyzed, and interpreted trends or patterns in complex data sets by leveraging analytical skills, finding correlations, and visualizing with charts, resulting in valuable insights for stakeholders.
- Processed large datasets and ran statistical analyses using SPSS software, ensuring accurate and reliable results for informed decision-making.

Database Administration Intern Rivers State ICT Department (Techcreek), Port Harcourt, Nigeria September 2020 - February 2021

Demonstrated leadership skills in managing projects from concept to completion, ensuring successful project delivery and team satisfaction.

- Demonstrated leadership skills in managing projects from concept to completion.
- Utilized strong analytical and problem-solving skills to develop effective solutions for challenging situations, resulting in improved processes and increased revenue.

Projects

Bedmate

It is a web application that allows individuals to facilitate connections and forge companionship that uplifts, inspires and enriches sexual adventures.

Mind Pal (To-do list app):

August 2021.

A to-do app that allows users to add task, edit tasks, delete tasks, update tasks(as completed) and set a reminder for each task.

Ecommerce WebApp July 2022

Created a fully functional web application that allows for the easy buying of goods and services over a wide region from the comfort of your own home.

Uber Trips Analysis with Python:

December 2022

- Conducted extensive analysis of Uber Trips data using Python, resulting in valuable insights that informed business decisions.
- Utilized advanced data processing and visualization packages such as Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn in Python to effectively analyze and communicate insights.

Whatsapp clone February 2022

Successfully developed and built working clone of the popular messaging application known as whatsapp.

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY – Salem University Lokoja – Kogi State, Nigeria August

2021

MAR 2023

Majors: Information Technology.

Certifications

JOBBERMAN SOFT-SKILLS CERTIFICATE **OCT 2021**

HIIT PYTHON PROGRAMMING CERTIFICATE **FEB 2022**

GIWOST HSE 123 CERTIFICATE MAR 2023

LOCTECH MERN STACK CERTIFICATE

GIWOST PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

SIDEHUSTLE MOBILE APP DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE **OCT 2021**